Guide to the John B. Snook Architectural Records Collection 1762-1948 PR 64
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Architectural Drawings, 1846-1948
  - Project #213: 381 Madison Street, New York, NY, 1895 (Box 39)
  - Project #214: 143 Broadway, New York, NY (Box 39)
  - Project #215: Bank Street and Wall Street, New York, NY (Box 39)
  - Project #216: Alfred Wagstaff, 591 Broadway, New York, NY (Folder FF 17)
  - Project #217: M. Kemper, Tenement, 179 East Broadway, New York, NY (Folder FF 18)
  - Project #218: Tenement, 248 Mulberry Street, New York NY, 1885 (Folder FF 19)
  - Project #219: 59 Spring Street, New York NY (Folder FF 20)
  - Project #220: Broome Street and Mulberry Street, New York, NY, 1884 (Folder FF 21)
  - Project #221: Motor Freight Terminal, 160 Bank Street, New York, NY (Folder FF 22)
  - Project #222: All Angels Church, New York, NY (Folder FF 23)
  - Project #223: A.T. Stewart, Store, Broadway at Reade Street, New York, NY, 1846 (Folder OS FF 26)
  - Project #224: Benjamin Tredwell, Store, 8 College Place, New York, NY, 1859 (Folder FF 27)
  - Project #225: NY & Harlem RR, NY Central RR, and Cornelius Vanderbilt, Grand Central Station, New York, NY, 1869 (Frame OS)
    General note
    This drawing is stored in an oversize frame, and access is restricted.
  - Index to Drawings by John B. Snook and John B Snook & Sons (Volume 1)
- Series II: Financial Records, 1843-1910
  Series II. Business Records includes 37 bound volumes, all but one are some form of financial and business records. One bound "Index to drawings by John B, Snook and John B. Snook & Sons" lists projects and drawings, but it can be difficult to match these to the projects for which drawings are available.
  - Account Book, 1860-1862 (Volume 2)
  - Account Book, 1862-1864 (Volume 3)
  - Account Book, 1864-1886 (Volume 4)
  - Account Book, 1868-1877 (Volume 5)
  - Account Book, 1877-1887 (Volume 6)
  - Account Book, 1887-1893 (Volume 7)
  - Account Book, 1887-1893 (Volume 8)
  - Contract Book, 1843-1855 (Volume 9)
  - Contract Book, 1855-1873 (Volume 10)
  - Contract Book, 1873-1882 (Volume 11)
  - Contract Book, 1883-1887 (Volume 12)
  - Contract Book, 1886-1892 (Volume 13)
  - Contract Book, 1892-1897 (Volume 14)
  - Daybook, 1887-1889 (Volume 15)
  - Daybook, 1889-1891 (Volume 16)
  - Daybook, 1891-1893 (Volume 17)
  - Daybook, 1894-1896 (Volume 18)
  - Daybook, 1896-1902 (Volume 19)
  - Daybook, 1902-1910 (Volume 20)
  - Ledger, 1845-1852 (Volume 21)
  - Ledger, 1850-1869 (Volume 22)
  - Ledger, 1861-1866 (Volume 23)
  - Ledger, 1866-1882 (Volume 24)
  - Ledger, 1883-1899 (Volume 25)
  - Ledger, 1887-1894 (Volume 26)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1865-1866 (Volume 27)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1866-1868 (Volume 28)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1868-1870 (Volume 29)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1871-1873 (Volume 30)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1873-1876 (Volume 31)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1876-1879 (Volume 32)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1879-1881 (Volume 33)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1882-1884 (Volume 34)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1884-1885 (Volume 35)
  - Receipts and Expenditures, 1885-1888 (Volume 36)
- Series III: Printed Material from Snook's Library, 1762-1928
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes volumes from the libraries of John Butler Snook and his descendents. Many of the items are fragile and/or damaged. The copies of "Mr. Vanderbilt's House and Collection" are in very poor condition.
  - Books in English, 1762-1928
    - The Mansions of England in the Olden Time, Vols. I-IV, by Joseph Nash, 1869 (Offsite-box 43)
    - A Dictionary of Architecture, Vols. 1-3, by Robert Stuart, 1854 (Offsite-box 40)
    - Letters of an Architect from France, Italy, and Greece, Vols. I-II, by Joseph Woods, 1828 (Offsite-box 41)
    - Art Studies in Nature as Applied to Design, by J. Glaisher, et al, 1872 (Offsite-box 40)
    - A Treatise on the Decorative Part of Civil Architecture, Vol. II, by William Chambers, 1825 (Offsite-box 41)
    - The Architectural Reprint, 8 Volumes, 1903-1904 (Offsite-box 43)
    - A Century in Construction, James Stewart and Company, publisher, 1944 (Offsite-box 42)
    - The Antiquities of Athens, by James Stuart and Nicholas Revett, 1762 (Offsite-box 57)
    - Designs for Carving and Gilding, by Thomas King, 1830-1850 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Designs for Cottage and Villa Architecture, by Samuel H. Brooks, 1839 (Offsite-box 41)
    - The Architect, Vol. IX, Jan-June 1873 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Elementary Principles of Carpentry, by Thomas Tredgold, 1820 (Offsite-box 41)
    - Open Timber Roofs of the Middle Ages, by D. Bogue, 1849 (Offsite-box 46)
    - The Parthenon Naos, by Ernest Flagg, 1937 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Missouri's Contribution to Architecture, by John Asbury Bryan, 1928 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Villa And Cottage Architecture, Blackie and Sons, publisher, 1868 (Offsite-box 46)
    - Historical Account of the Glasgow Cathedral, by J. Collie, 1836 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Artists' Homes, by Maurice B. Adams, 1883 (Offsite-box 51)
    - The Cathedrals of the World, Vols.1-2, by Fred H. Allen, 1886 (Offsite-box 51)
    - The Architecture of M. Vitruvius Pollio, translated by William Newton, 1791 (Offsite-box 44)
    - Reliques of Ancient English Architecture, by John Johnson, 1858 (Offsite-box 52)
    - The Terra-Cotta Architecture of North Italy, by Lewis Gruner, 1867 (Offsite-box 52)
    - Examples of Carved Oak Woodwork of the 16th and 17th Centuries, by William Bliss Sanders, 1883 (Offsite-box 53)
    - English Interior Woodwork, by Henry Tanner, 1903 (Offsite-box 53)
    - Churches and Royal Monasteries of Batalhas, by Luis De Sousa and James Murphy, 1836 (Offsite-box 57)
    - Later Renaissance Architecture in England, Vols. I-III, by John Belcher and Mervyn E. Macartney, 1897-1901 (Offsite-box 54)
    - Later Renaissance Architecture in England, Vols. IV-VI, by John Belcher and Mervyn E. Macartney, 1897-1901 (Offsite-box 55)
    - Mr. Vanderbilt's House and Collection, George Barrie, publisher (2 volumes), 1883-1884 (Offsite-box 58)
    - Mr. Vanderbilt's House and Collection, George Barrie, publisher (2 volumes), 1883-1884 (Offsite-box 59)
    - Mr. Vanderbilt's House and Collection, George Barrie, publisher (2 volumes), 1883-1884 (Offsite-box 60)
    - Picturesque and Descriptive Views of the City of Dublin by James Malton, 1791 (Offsite-box 56)
    - Plans, Elevations and Sections of Buildings Public and Private, Executed in England, by David Laing, 1818 (Offsite-box 50)
    - History of Woburn Abbey, by P.F. Robinson, 1833 (Offsite-box 56)
  - Books in French, 1812-1872
    - Traite de Construction Appliquee a L'Architecture Civile, by J.A. Borgnis, 1840 (Offsite-box 47)
    - L'Architecture Privee au XIX Siecle, Vols. 1-3, by Cesar Daly, 1864 (Offsite-box 49)
    - L'Architecture Privee au XIX Siecle, Vols. 1-3, by Cesar Daly, 1872 (Offsite-box 48)
    - Motifs Historiques D'Architecture et De Sculpture D'Ornement Vols.1-2, by Cesar Daly, 1871 (Offsite-box 47)
    - Eglises de Bourgs et Villages, by A. Baudot, 1867 (Offsite-box 46)
    - Recueil D'Architecture Civile, by J. Ch. Krafft, 1812 (Offsite-box 57)
  - Books in German, 1840-1887
    - Architektonischen Ordnungen de Griechen und Romer, by J.M. Mauch, 1872 (Offsite-box 42)
    - Die Bauformen des Mittelalters in Sandstein by Adolph Opderbecke, 1882 (Offsite-box 47)
    - Tektonik der Hellenen, by Karl Boetticher, 1873 (Offsite-box 44)
    - Vorlegeblatter fur Maurer und Zimmerleute: Nachtrage in 37 Lithographierten Tafeln mit Erlauterungen Entworfen, by Gustav Stier, 1844 (Offsite-box 44)
    - Architektonische Entwurfe zu Pracht- und Civil-Gebauden, by Bartels, Bauer, et al, 1846 (Offsite-box 44)
    - Archiv fur Natur, Kunst, Wissenschaft, und Leben, by Ochme & Muller, 1840-1842 (Offsite-box 41)
    - Architektonisches Skizzen-Buch (5 bound volumes plus 11 issues), by Ernst and Korn, 1855-1876 (Offsite-box 45)
    - Potsdam, by F. Riegel, 1842 (Offsite-box 56)
    - Decorativer Ziegelbau, by Hermann Bethke, 1887 (Offsite-box 50)
  - Books in Italian, 1826-1840
    - La Casa di Delizia, by Alessandro Gherardesca, 1826 (Offsite-box 49)
    - Capitolo, by A. Desgodetz, circa 1840 (Offsite-box 53)